[Music]
foreign
this is our lesson three
if you compare with the advanced level
Trading but as an overall present
testoster automation training it's a
lesson 80.
so in this lesson I'm gonna teach you
how can you link automated test cases to
your
requirements by using trisentis Tasker
latest version 16.
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
so by end of this lesson
you learn how to link test cases to your
requirements in Tosca
and you learn how to link execution
lists to your requirements
so by linking your test cases and
execution lists to your requirements you
will get an overview of the progress and
the entire state of your
project
so this is as same as as similar as
traceability Matrix where you can track
requirement coverage and the execution
state
so now let's jump onto the system and
let me show you how can you link your
automated test cases and your execution
list to your requirements by using
latest version Tasker 16.
so before we uh start
um linking test cases to requirements
right so this is my Tasker 16 tool okay
let's let us understand very high level
about the requirements okay so I've
already listed out all the webshop
front-end requirements in the
requirements tab okay so basically uh we
will I created
requirements right click on top right
requirements right click I created
a folder requirement folder called
webshop requirements under webshop
requirement folder after you've created
requirements set
okay
webshop front-end requirement set right
click on the folder and this is set and
this is your folder okay I created a
requirement set
under this again I have created a
requirement
okay called customer tasks so under this
requirement again I have created four
different requirements register login
modify customer data
check order in the same way handle
product there are four requirements
shopping cart there are four
requirements order process there are
four requirements okay so now this is
all about the requirements I've already
created requirements now to link your
test cases to requirements let us first
move these requirements to the split
screen okay split screen view
okay so these are the requirements okay
and now
we need to link the test cases so what
test cases I'm going to link
see the test cases from session 13
the automated test case from uh Dynamic
text numbers and the automated test
cases from uh discount code so I'm going
to map all these three requirements okay
to the corresponding requirement on
right side
okay so first
shopping
costs so I'm gonna drag this and drop to
the
calculate shopping cost requirement okay
and I have linked this okay and then
this payment process I'm gonna drag this
test case
to payment method requirement
okay so that is linked so if you see the
test case is linked
and now the discount code
I'm gonna map this to discounts under
shopping carts right drag
and drop it to under shopping carts to
discounts
okay I have mapped this so now we have
mapped three test cases to the
corresponding requirements okay
and then
it's not enough to map just test cases
we need to map the execution List actual
execution list if you see here
all those test cases in my previous
session I have already explained you
in my previous session creating the
execution list right I have created an
execution list and where I have mapped
all these three test cases to that
execution list okay so now we have to
map this execution list to the
requirement the parent requirement okay
so we need to now
map your execution list called webshop
to your requirement set this is your
requirement set under requirement set
called friend webshop front end we have
all the sub requirements this is your
set so your execution list
should be linked to your requirement set
okay so drag
the requirement set
sorry your exhibition list to
requirement set
so done
so now
our test cases are maputo requirements
and the corresponding execution list
also mapped requirement so now let's go
back to our
full
view of our requirements okay full we
have our requirements so if you see here
my full view So based on my previous
uh based on my previous execution runs
if you see here
we mapped one
test case under this so that is what the
discounts and then we mapped two test
cases under order process if you see
here coverage specified so that means
if you map the test cases
for all these four five requirements
then your coverage will be 100 for now
it's showing 49 because you only mapped
this 100 and this one is only 20 okay
and if you see here this will be mapped
one more okay out of
four requirements we only mapped
one
out of which because of my previous runs
it is showing as failed that's why you
can see the coverage of the specified
requirement
and execution State 20 percent failed 49
percent failed right
for this requirement it's 100 failed
correct so basically
as soon as you map your test cases and
your execution list now you can track
your entire requirement state
in terms of coverage
in terms of execution
state
okay so this gives you overall
traceability Matrix and your overall
project status also each requirement
what is the coverage and each
requirement what is the execution state
right once you map all of your test
cases to your
uh requirements and your execution list
to your requirement that's it so you can
simply track your entire project State
based on that okay so hope you all
understand the concept of how to link
your test cases and your execution list
to your requirements so one thing is you
need as soon as you link your test cases
you need to link your execution list or
so to your requirements because whenever
I execute my execution list the
corresponding test cases will be mapped
I mean the corresponding test cases will
be reporting to your requirements pass
or fail right
so if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries thank you hope
you all understand the concepts of how
to link automated test cases and your
execution list to your requirements
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank you
[Music]